Amsterdam Area
The Netherlands

→ +31 6 26225563

→ alex.rodiontsev@gmail.com
• alex.rodiontsev
• github.com/klappvisor
• mylifeecho.com

# Alexey Rodiontsev

## Personal Data

Name Alexey Rodiontsev

Date of Birth 07.03.1989

Marital status Married, without children

Nationality Russian

# Summary

Software engineer since 2011 with strong knowledge and interest in OOP and functional programming, SOLID principles, Design patterns, modern technologies in software development. Polyglot programmer with main focus on Java/C# and interest in modern functional languages. Good experience in design and development of web applications using .NET technology stack as well as JVM: all layers, from database to business logic and user interface.

Expertice in Media Streaming Security.

Microsoft Certified Solution Developer: Web Applications (MCSD).

Worked mainly in international teams following Agile (Scrum, Kanban) techniques.

Interested in cloud and web development, functional programming and continuous education.

## — Professional Skills

#### Technical skills

Generic OOP, Functional programming, SOLID, Design patterns, Agile (Scrum, Kanban)

Programming C#, Java, Scala, JavaScript, Python, Haskell

languages

#### Technologies and frameworks

Java Java 7/8, Jersey, JPA, Hibernate, Spring, Guice, Jetty

C#/.NET ASP.NET MVC, LINQ, Entity Framework, WCF(SOAP/REST)

Web JQuery, React.js, Backbone.js, Underscore.js, HTML, CSS, AJAX

Databases MS SQL, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Redis, SQLite

Tools

IDE IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio, Vim

Others Docker, Jenkins, AWS, GIT, Subversion, Maven, Gradle

OS Windows, Linux(Ubuntu, CentOS)

# Employment History

Irdeto B.V.

APR 2015— Senior Software Engineer, Irdeto B.V

PRESENT Worked on video security product written in Java 8 in functional style, integrated with multiple streaming technologies.

Important role in all aspects of product development, design and work on new functionality, integration with different DRM systems and other products.

One of the main contributors to shared source code project within the company used internally by different teams.

Nov Software Engineer, Irdeto B.V

2013-Apr Development of scalable, high performance RESTful API for full text search of video

2015 content metadata (migration from existing SQL and C# based legacy solution to Elasticsearh and Java based one).

Key role in design and development of integration with Elasticsearch.

Working in the international team of 4 software and 2 QA engineers.

Sibers Group, Ltd

MAY Senior .NET Software Developer, Sibers Group, Ltd

2011–Nov Passed through the all steps from junior to senior developer.

2013 Took a major part in full development life cycle of several projects based on .NET Framework. New projects estimation and work with trainees.

## Professional Experience

July 2015 – Media Security System, at Irdeto B.V

PRESENT Backend Video content security system integrated with multiple media streaming technologies such as HLS, CENC/DASH and DRM systems: PlayReady, Widevine, FairPlay, Adobe Primetime, inhouse system.

Extensively using functional programming techniques.

Responsibilities Adopted functional programming for Java together with other engineers to deliver

high quality code.

Important role in all aspects of product development: design and coding new features, integration with number of media streaming technologies and DRM systems.

Key role in speading knowladge within the team and building cross-functional team. Participated in building CI infrastructure based on Jenkins and Docker, performance testing. One of the main contributors to shared source code project within the company used internally by different teams.

Technologies Java 8, Scala, Hibernate via JPA, PostgreSQL, Guice, Jersey, TestNG, Jetty, Maven, Amazon EC2

Jan 2016 – Telegram Bot API for Haskell, presonal open source project

Technologies Haskell, Servant, HSpec, Stack, CircleCI

NOVEMBER Search & Discovery, at Irdeto B.V.

2013–July REST and Java API to search video content metadata presented in the system, part 2015 of OTT solution. Migration from C# and SQL solution to Java and ElasticSearch

Responsibilities Design and development of scalable REST and Java API on top of ElasticSearch for full text search. started from proof of concept to fully functional solution, designed Search DSL.

Responsible for interaction with ElasticSearch (writing and optimizing search queries and correct document analysis), performance, load and stress testing

Technologies Java 7/8, ElasticSearch, Spring, Jersey, Jetty, Maven, JUnit, Amazon EC2, BlazeMeter/JMeter

2012–2013 Online photo album editor, at Sibers

Online photoalbum editor with server side rendering

Responsibilities Design and implementation of application following to SaaS approach, implementation of GDI+ image renderer. Single page application using Backbone.js, HTML5, CSS3, integration with Picasa/Google+ and Facebook

Technologies ASP.NET MVC 4/Web API, EF Code First, GDI+, Backbone.js, Twitter Bootstrap, Google API, Facebook Graph API, HTML5, CSS3

2011–2012 Medical system for self diagnostics, at Sibers

Development of medical system for self-diagnosis based on Orchard CMS.

Responsibilities Database design, implementation of Orchard CMS modules for the system, mobile web version based on jQuery Mobile, integration with Google API

Technologies Orchard CMS, Fluent NHibernate, WCF WebApi, iTextSharp, jQuery, jQuery Mobile, Google Maps, Google Analytics

#### **Education**

2010–2012 M.Sc. Physics, Novosibirsk State University, Novosibirsk, Russia

2006–2010 B.Sc. Physics, Novosibirsk State University, Novosibirsk, Russia

#### Certifications

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer: Web Applications MCSD, Transcript ID: 1035553, Access Code: AlexRodiontsev, (verification)

Microsoft Specialist: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 MS

Independent Coursework (with certificate of accomplishment)

#### Coursera

Aug 2013 Cryptography I, Stanford University

Aug 2013 Algorithms: Design and Analysis, Part 1, Stanford University

SEPT 2013 Startup Engineering, Stanford University

DEC 2014 Functional Programming Principles in Scala, Ecole Polytechnique

## June 2015 Principles of Reactive Programming, Ecole Polytechnique

### $\operatorname{ed}X$

Jan 2016 Introduction to Functional Programming, DelftX, FP101x

Aug 2015 Scalable Machine Learning, BerkeleyX, CS190.1x

July 2015 Introduction to Big Data with Apache Spark, BerkeleyX, CS100.1x

Sept 2013 Software as a Service, BerkeleyX, CS169.2x

Oct 2012 Software as a Service, BerkeleyX, CS169.1x

## **L**anguages

English Technical, Good reading, written and verbal skills

Russian Native